<article>
	<preamble>infoEmbeddings.pdf</preamble>
	<titre>An Empirical Evaluation of Text Representation Schemes on</titre>
	<auteurs>
		<auteur>
			<nom>Multilingual Social</nom>
			<mail>sjmodha@gmail.com</mail>
			<affiliation></affiliation>
		</auteur>
		<auteur>
			<nom>Web to Filter</nom>
			<mail>prasenjit.majumder@gmail.comar</mail>
			<affiliation></affiliation>
		</auteur>
		<auteur>
			<nom>Textual Aggression</nom>
			<mail>N/A</mail>
			<affiliation></affiliation>
		</auteur>
	</auteurs>
	<abstract></abstract>
	<introduction>The Social Web is a great source for studying human interaction and behavior. Inthe last few years, there is an exponential growth in Social Media user base. Sensingcontent of Social Media like Facebook, Twitter, by the smart autonomous applicationempower its user community with real-time information which is unfolded across thedierent part of the world. Social media provide the easiest and anonymous platformfor common people to voice their opinion or view on a various entity like celebrity,politician, product, stock market etc or any social movement. Sometime such opinionsmight be aggressive in nature and propagate hate in the social media community.With the unprecedented increase in the user base of the social media and its availability on the Smartphones, incidents like Hate speech, trolling, Cyberbullying, andAggressive posts are increasing exponentially. A smart autonomous system is requiredwhich enable surveillance on the social media platform and detect such incidents.Some of the researchers look posts from the aspect like aggression Kumar Ritesh etal. (2018) to lter the contents. some of the posts contain words which might be qualied as either highly or overly aggressive or have hidden aggression. Sometimes postsdo not have any aggression. Based on these, posts or comments are categorized intothree classes namely: `Overtly Aggressive`, `Covertly Aggressiveànd `Non-aggressive`Kumar Ritesh et al. (2018). Henceforth, in the rest of the paper, we will denote theseclasses by these abbreviations namely: OAG, CAG, NAG respectively.Table 1 showsthe sample posts belonging to these classes.Social Media, specically Microblog has proved its importance during the disasterrelated incidents like an earthquake, Hurricane and oods1. Organizations involvedin relief operation actively track posts related to situational information posted onFacebook and Twitter during the disaster. However, At the same time, social mediais ooded with lots of prayer and condolence messages. Posts which contain factualinformation are extremely important for the organization involved in post-disasterrelief operations for coordination. Filtering and Ranking of the posts containing factualinformation will be very useful to them. We believe that this is the special problemof the Sentiment Analysis task. We consider this problem as a combination of twoclass classication problem: factual posts and nob-factual posts plus Ranking. Table</introduction>
	<discussion>the future work in section 8.</discussion>
	<conclusion>In this Paper, Multilingual Social media stream is studied with special kind of textfeatures: Aggression and fact perspective. Exhaustive experiments are performed tobenchmark the text representation scheme on machine learning classiers and deepneural nets. From the results, we conclude that deep Neural model with pre-trainedword embedding is the better choice than machine earning classier and transfer learning model. Word embedding is the better text representative scheme than Bag-of-wordsfor the deep neural models. In fact, performance can be improved with the help of fastText pre-trained vector. However, machine learning classiers perform better in BoWwith TF/IDF weighting than word embedding. We also concluded that higher dropout will help to counter model overtting and improvise a standard evaluation metrics.CNN and LSTM are the better models for these datasets. On the English test corpus,we obtained a better weighted F1score for NAG class and poor weighted F1scorefor CAG class which supports the previous (Malmasi, et al. , 2017) ndings. For theFacebook Hindi test corpus, the same seems not to be true. We obtained a better F1score for CAG class than NAG class. It is also to be noted that the model leads topoor result on Twitter test data since the training corpus was created from Facebook.In such cases, deep neural models substantially outperform machine learning classiers. Signicance test conrms these claims with 95 % condence interval in most thecases. Our work shows what kind of problems are moving into the center of attentionfor research in machine learning. Using deep learning models, there is great potentialto solve some of these problems, yet still, the performance is far from perfect. Modeltransfer between problems and the application of derived knowledge in user interfacesare areas directions for future work.</conclusion>
	<biblio> Aroyehun, Segun Taofeek and Gelbukh, Alexander (2018). Aggression detection in social media: Using deep neural networks, data augmentation, and pseudolabeling .Proceedings of the First Workshop on Trolling, Aggression and Cyberbullying (TRAC-2018) , pp.90{97. Arroyo-Fern andez, Ignacio and Forest, Dominic and Torres-Moreno, Juan-Manuel and Carrasco-Ruiz, Mauricio and Legeleux, Thomas and Joannette,Karen (2018). Cyberbullying Detection Task: the EBSI-LIA-UNAM System (ELU) at COLING'18 TRAC-1 .Proceedings of the First Workshop on Trolling,Aggression and Cyberbullying (TRAC-2018) , pp 140{149. Basu, Moumitaand Ghosh, Saptarshi and Ghosh, Kripabandhu (2018). Overview of the FIRE 2018 track: Information Retrieval from Microblogs during Disasters (IRMiDis) .Proceedings of FIRE 2018 - Forum for Information Retrieval Evaluation , Gujrat, India, December . Baziotis, Christos and Pelekis, Nikos and Doulkeridis, Christos (2017). Datastories at semeval2017 task 4: Deep lstm with attention for message-level and topic-based sentiment analysis . Proceedings of the 11th International Workshop on Semantic Evaluation (SemEval-2017) , pp.747{754 Bojanowski, Piotr and Grave, Edouard and Joulin, Armand and Mikolov, Tomas (2017) Enriching word vectors with subword information ,Transactions of the Association for Computational Linguistics , vol-5,pp.135{146, MIT Press. Burnap, Pete and Williams, Matthew Ltitle (2015). Cyber hate speech on twitter: An application of machine classication and statistical modeling for policy and decision makingPolicy & Internet , vol-7 number 2, pp.223{242, Wiley Online Library. Conover, Michael and Ratkiewicz, Jacob and Francisco, Matthew R and Gon calves , Bruno and Menczer, Filippo and Flammini, Alessandro (2011). Political polarization on twitter. ,Icwsm , vol-133, pp.89{96. 19Conover, Michael D and Gon calves, Bruno and Ratkiewicz, Jacob and Flammini, Alessandro and Menczer, Filippo (2011). Predicting the political alignment of twitter users ,Privacy, Security, Risk and Trust (PASSAT) and 2011 IEEE Third Inernational Conference on Social Computing (SocialCom), 2011 IEEE Third International Conference on , pp.192{199. Davidson, Thomas and Warmsley, Dana and Macy, Michael and Weber, Ingmar (2017). Automated Hate Speech Detection and the Problem of Oensive Langemuage .Proceedings of ICWSM . Deriu, Jan and Gonzenbach, Maurice and Uzdilli, Fatih and Lucchi, Aurelien and Luca, Valeria De and Jaggi, Martin (2016). Swisscheese at semeval-2016 task 4: Sentiment classication using an ensemble of convolutional neural networks with distant supervision .Proceedings of the 10th international workshop on semantic evaluation ,pp.1124{1128. Hltcoe, J (2013). Semeval-2013 task 2: Sentiment analysis in Twitter ,vol-312 Atlanta, Georgia, USA. Howard, Jeremy & Ruder, Sebastian 2018. Universal language model ne-tuning for text classication" ,arXiv preprint arXiv:1801.06146 , Harris, Zellig S (1954), Distributional structure Word,10, number=2-3,pp.146{162, 1954, Taylor & Francis. Kumar, Ritesh and Reganti, Aishwarya N. and Bhatia, Akshit and Maheshwari,Tushar (2018), Aggression-annotated Corpus of Hindi-English Code-mixed Data ,Proceedings of the 11th Language Resources and Evaluation Conference (LREC) , Miyazaki, Japan. Kumar, Ritesh and Ojha, Atul Kr. and Malmasi, Shervin and Zampieri Marcos (2018). Benchmarking Aggression Identication in Social Media, Proceedings of the First Workshop on Trolling, Aggression and Cyberbulling (TRAC), Santa Fe, USA Kwok, Irene and Wang, Yuzhou (2013),Locate the hate: Detecting Tweets Against Blacks ,Twenty-Seventh AAAI Conference on Articial Intelligence . Lau, Jey Han and Baldwin, Timothy (2016). An empirical evaluation of doc2vec with practical insights into document embedding generation .arXiv preprint arXiv:1607.05368 . Le, Quoc and Mikolov, Tomas (2014) Distributed representations of sentences and documents .International Conference on Machine Learning , pp.1188{1196 Majumder, Prasenjit and Mandl, Thomas and Modha Sandip (2018) Filtering Aggression from the Multilingual Social Media Feed Proceedings of the First Workshop on Trolling, Aggression and Cyberbullying (TRAC-2018) , pp. 199{207 Malmasi, Shervin and Zampieri, Marcos (2017) Detecting Hate Speech in Social Media Proceedings of the International Conference Recent Advances in Natural Language Processing (RANLP) , pp.467{472. Malmasi, Shervin and Zampieri, Marcos (2018). Challenges in Discriminating Profanity from Hate Speech Journal of Experimental & Theoretical Articial Intelligence pp.1{16, vol-30, issue-2,Taylor & Francis. Maynard, Diana and Funk, Adam (2011) Automatic detection of political opinionsin tweets , Extended Semantic Web Conference ,pp. 88{99, Springer . Mikolov, Tomas and Chen, Kai and Corrado, Greg and Dean, Jerey (2013). Ecient estimation of word representations in vector space ,arXiv preprint arXiv:1301.3781 . Mikolov, Tomas and Grave, Edouard and Bojanowski, Piotr and Puhrsch, Christian and Joulin, Armand (2018). Advances in Pre-Training Distributed Word Representations ,Proceedings of the International Conference on Language Resources and Evaluation (LREC 2018) . Modha, Sandip and Agrawal, Krati and Verma, Deepali and Majumder, Prasenjit and Mandalia, Chintak 2016. DAIICT at TREC RTS 2016: Live Push Notication and Email Digest.,TREC. Mohammad, Saif M and Kiritchenko, Svetlana and Zhu, Xiaodan (2013). NRC-Canada: Building the state-of-the-art in sentiment analysis of tweets.arXiv preprint arXiv:1308.6242 . Nakov, Preslav and Ritter, Alan and Rosenthal, Sara and Sebastiani, Fabrizio and Stoyanov, Veselin (2016). SemEval-2016 task 4: Sentiment analysis in Twitter ,Proceedings of the 10th international workshop on semantic evaluation (semeval-2016) , pp. 1{18. Pennington, Jerey and Socher, Richard and Manning, Christopher Glove: Global vectors for 20word representation Proceedings of the 2014 conference on empirical methods in natural language processing (EMNLP) , pp.1532{1543. Peters, Matthew E and Neumann, Mark and Iyyer, Mohit and Gardner, Matt and Clark, Christopher and Lee, Kenton and Zettlemoyer, Luke (2018). Deep contextualized word representations arXiv preprint arXiv:1802.05365 . Razavi, Amir H and Inkpen, Diana and Uritsky, Sasha and Matwin, Stan (2010) Oensive language detection using multi-level classication ,Canadian Conference on Articial Intelligence pp.16{27, Springer Rosenthal, Sara and Nakov, Preslav and Kiritchenko, Svetlana and Mohammad, Saif and Ritter, Alan and Stoyanov, Veselin (2015). Semeval-2015 task 10: Sentiment analysis in twitter Proceedings of the 9th international workshop on semantic evaluation (SemEval 2015) , pp.451{463. Rosenthal, Sara and Farra, Noura and Nakov, Preslav (2017). SemEval-2017 task 4: Sentiment analysis in Twitter Proceedings of the 11th International Workshop on Semantic Evaluation (SemEval-2017) , pp.502{518. Schmidt, Anna and Wiegand, Michael (2017). A Survey on Hate Speech Detection Using Natural Language Processing ,Proceedings of the Fifth International Workshop on Natural Language Processing for Social Media. Association for Computational Linguistics Valencia, Spain, pp.1{10, Severyn, Aliaksei and Moschitti, Alessandro (2015) Unitn: Training deep convolutional neural network for twitter sentiment classication ,Proceedings of the 9th international workshop on semantic evaluation (SemEval 2015) , pp. 464{469. Tumasjan, Andranik and Sprenger, Timm Oliver and Sandner, Philipp G and Welpe, Isabell M (2010). Predicting elections with twitter: What 140 characters reveal about political sentiment. ,Icwsm , vol-10, number-1, pp. 178{185. Warner, William and Hirschberg, Julia (2012) Detecting hate speech on the world wide web , Proceedings of the Second Workshop on Language in Social Media ,pp 19{26,Association for Computational Linguistics. Xu, Jun-Ming and Jun, Kwang-Sung and Zhu, Xiaojin and Bellmore, Amy (2012). Learning from bullying traces in social media ,Proceedings of the 2012 conference of the North American chapter of the association for computational linguistics: Human language technologies , pp.656{666, Association for Computational Linguistics Zhang, Ye and Wallace, Byron (2015). A Sensitivity Analysis of (and Practitioners' Guide to) Convolutional Neural Networks for Sentence Classication ,arXiv preprint arXiv:1510.03820 . Majumder, Prasenjit and Mitra, Mandar and Pal, Dipasree and Bandyopadhyay, Ayan and Maiti, Samaresh and Mitra, Sukanya and Sen, Aparajita and Pal, Sukomal. Text collections for FIRE ,Proceedings of the 31st annual international ACM SIGIR conference on research and development in information retrieval ,pp.699{700,ACM Majumdar, P and Mitra, Mandar and Parui, Swapan K and Bhattacharya, Initiative for indian language ir evaluation ,The First International Workshop on Evaluating Information Access (EVIA) 21</biblio>
</article>