<article>
	<preamble>Iria_Juan-Manuel_Gerardo.pdf</preamble>
	<titre>On the Development of the RST Spanish Treebank</titre>
	<auteurs>
		<auteur>
			<nom>Iria da Cunha</nom>
			<mail>gsierram@iingen.unam.</mail>
			<affiliation></affiliation>
		</auteur>
		<auteur>
			<nom>Juan-Manuel</nom>
			<mail>iria.dacunha@upf.edu</mail>
			<affiliation></affiliation>
		</auteur>
		<auteur>
			<nom>Torres-Moreno</nom>
			<mail></mail>
			<affiliation></affiliation>
		</auteur>
		<auteur>
			<nom>Gerardo Sierra</nom>
			<mail></mail>
			<affiliation></affiliation>
		</auteur>
	</auteurs>
	<abstract>  In this article we present the RST Spanish  Treebank, the first corpus annotated with  rhetorical relations for this language. We  describe the characteristics of the corpus,  the annotation criteria, the annotation  procedure, the inter-annotator agreement,  and other related aspects. Moreover, we  show the interface that we have developed  to carry out searches over the corpus’  annotated texts.  </abstract>
	<introduction> The Rhetorical Structure Theory (RST) (Mann and Thompson, 1988) is a language independent theory based on the idea that a text can be segmented into  Elementary Discourse Units (EDUs) linked by means of nucleus-satellite or multinuclear rhetorical relations. In the first case, the satell ite gives additional information about the other one, the nucleus, on which it depends (ex. Result, Condition, Elaboration or Concession). In the second case, several elements, all nuclei, are connected at the same level, that is, there are no elements dependent on others and they all have the same importance with regard to the intentions of the author of the text (ex. Contrast, List, Joint o r Sequence). The rhetorical analysis of a text by means of RST includes 3 phases: segmentation, detection of relations and building of hierarchical  rhetorical trees. For more information about RST we recommend the original article of Mann and Thompson (1988), the web site of RST 1 and the RST review by Taboada and Mann (2006a). RST has been used to develop several applications, like automatic summarization, information extraction (IE), text generation, question-answering, automatic translation, etc. (Taboada and Mann, 2006b). Nevertheless, most of these works have been developed for English, German or Portuguese. This is due to the fact that at present corpora annotated with RST relations are  available only for these languages (for English: Carlson et al., 2002, Taboada and Renkema, 2008; for German: Stede, 2004; for Portuguese: Pardo et al., 2008) and there are automatic RST parsers for two of them (for English: Marcu, 2000; for Portuguese: Pardo et al., 2008) or automatic RST segmenters (for English: Tofiloski et al., 2009). Scientific community working on RST applied to Spanish is very small. For example, Bouayad-Agha et al. (2006) apply RST to text generation in several languages, Spanish among them. Da Cunha et al. (2007) develop a summarization system for medical texts in Spanish based on RST. Da Cunha and Iruskieta (2010) perform a contrastive analysis  of Spanish and Basque texts. Romera (2004) analyzes coherence relations by means of RST in spoken Spanish. Taboada (2004) applies RST to analyze the resources used by speakers to elaborate  conversations in English and Spanish.  We consider that it is necessary to build a Spanish corpus annotated by means of RST. This corpus should be useful for the development of a rhetorical parser for this language and several oth er applications related to computational linguistics, like those developed for other languages                                                            1 http://www.sfu.ca/rst/index.html 1(automatic translation, automatic summarization, IE, etc.). And that is what we pretend to achieve with our work. We present the development of the RST Spanish Treebank, the first Spanish corpus annotated by means of RST. In Section 2, we present the state of the art about RST annotated corpora. In Section 3, we explain the characteristics of the RST Spanish Treebank. In Section 4, we show the search interface we have developed. In Section 5, we establish some conclusions and future work.  </introduction>
	<discussion> verify if the difficulties were solved. This proces s was doubly interesting, since it helped to create common criteria for the annotation of the final corpus and to define the annotation criteria more clearly and consensually, in order to include them in the RST Spanish Treebank annotation manual. Once annotators agreed on the most difficult cases,  we consider that the training phase finished. 3.5 Designing and Managing the Annotation Procedure We start from the following annotation definition:   </discussion>
	<conclusion> and Future Work We think that this work means an important step for the RST research in Spanish, and that the RST Spanish Treebank will be useful to carry out diverse researches about RST in this language, from a descriptive point of view (ex. analysis of texts from different domains or genres) and an applied point of view (development of discourse parsers and NLP applications, like automatic summarization, automatic translation, IE, etc.).  For the moment the corpus' size is acceptable and, though the percentage of double-annotated texts is not very high, we think that having 10 annotators (using the same annotation manual) avoids the bias of only one annotator. In addition,  the corpus includes texts of diverse domains and genres, which provides us with a heterogeneous Spanish corpus. Moreover, the corpus interface that we have designed allows the user to select a subcorpus and to analyze it statistically. In addition, we think that it is essential to release a free corpus, on-line and dynamic, that is, in continuous growth. Nevertheless, we are conscious that our work still has certain limitations, which we will try to solve in the future. In the short term,  we have 5 aims:   a) To add one more annotator for the test corpus and to measure inter-annotator agreement. b) To use more agreement measures, like kappa. c) To reach a consensus on the annotation of the test corpus, in order to establish a set of texts considered as a preliminary gold standard. d) To finish and to evaluate the IE tool. e) To analyze the corpus to extract linguistic patterns for the automatic relations detection.  In the long term, we consider other aims:  f) To increase the corpus, by adding nonspecialized texts, and new domains and genres. g) To annotate all the texts by 3 people, to get a representative gold-standard for Spanish (this aim will depend on the funding of the project).  8References  Ron Artstein, and Massimo Poesio. 2008. Survey Article: Inter-Coder Agreement for Computational Linguistics. Computational Linguistics, 34(4):555 </conclusion>
	<biblio>  </biblio>
</article>
